Alison Reilly

reillyamr@gmail.com

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/alisonreilly | Github github.com/Tsunamins | Portfolio alisonreilly.dev

Experienced in Fullstack Software Engineering with a background in hospitality. Possess strong skills in critical thinking and need anticipation that help large enterprise companies drive sales and customer experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Typescript
React
Java
Python
Redis
Selenium
Jest
JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer I, Parchment (acquired by Instructure 2/1/2024), Remote 9/2022 - present

- Built a front end component library with React and Typescript, improving development speed and UI standardization
- Increased reliability and safeguarded future changes by writing unit tests with React testing-library and Jest
- Integrated on an additional team, learning Java and Spring Boot for background services and full stack applications
- Created new API endpoints with Spring Boot, Hibernate and Lombok, modified data with Liquibase

Software Engineer I, American Express, Remote 12/2021 – 9/2022

- Added front end features for an enterprise automations platform using React and company design library
- Implemented API routes in Golang and Python with Flask, concentrating on value add reporting for leadership
- Integrated a Redis Client speeding up reporting and other endpoint processing times
- Improved automated UI testing coverage by adding Gitlab pipeline Selenium Browser tests

Technical Support Engineer, ServiceNow, Remote 3/2021 - 12/2021

- Utilized platform debugging tools to identify conflicting security rules and other platform settings
- Employed Chrome Dev Tools, platform tools and other techniques for client side and server side debugging
- Increased ticket resolution speed by coordinating consultations with Customers, team members and developers
- Created knowledge base articles on findings enhancing the available support documentation for users and employees

Backend Developer Intern, 1909 Coworking, Remote 8/2020 - 03/2020

Internship project building middleware and integrations

- Integrated OfficeRnd & Salesforce REST APIs using NodeJS and Firebase functions
- Routed web hook response of OfficeRnd with ExpressJS ensuring separation of concerns
- Communicated goals with product owner and other 1909 team members on a bi-weekly basis to sync goals

EDUCATION

Flatiron School 1/2019 - 03/2020

Software Engineering: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, React, Redux

LaGuardia Community College, Long Island City, NY 3/2013 - 08/2017

Math and Science classes taken with Calculus, C++, Biology and writing concentrations

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Fauxtel Hotels - https://github.com/Tsunamins/FauxtelHotels | https://youtu.be/G4u KgDfBYI

- P project from Flatiron School Software Engineering program, updated and maintained with latest packages
- Created a mock hotel website with reservation features using React, Redux toolkit, react-day-picker
- Added JWT token-based authentication and authorization, confirmed new accounts with email verification
- Built an API backend using Ruby on Rails for data associations with PostgreSQL database, utilized fast_isonapi